Guide to the Meyer Schapiro Collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Correspondence, 1920s-2001
  - L
    - Lasky, Melvin J., 1945-1966 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Laufman, Sidney, 1978-1985 (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Lavin, Irving, 1974-1992 (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Lebensztejn, Jean-Claude, 1968-1995 (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Le Clair, Charles, 1941-1949 (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Lee, Rensselaer W. (Rensselaer Wright), 1944-1955 (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - Léger, Fernand, 1942-1944 (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - Lehmann-Haupt, Hellmut, 1927-1962 (Box 143, Folder 9)
    - Lehmann, James H., 1973-1983 (Box 143, Folder 10)
    - Leibovici, Marcel, 1959 (Box 143, Folder 11)
    - Leibowitz, René, 1950-1952 (Box 143, Folder 12)
    - Leites, Nathan, 1949 (Box 143, Folder 13)
    - Lejwa, Madeleine Chalette, 1973 (Box 143, Folder 14)
    - Lennon, John and Yoko Ono, circa 1970s (Box 143, Folder 15)
    - Leroy, Paul and Anne Elizabeth, 1952-1953 (Box 143, Folder 16)
    - Lethem, Richard, 1979-1992 (Box 143, Folder 17)
    - Levaillant, Françoise, 1973-1978 (Box 143, Folder 18)
    - Lévi-Strauss, Claude, 1944-1963 (Box 143, Folder 19)
    - Levi, Doro, 1940 (Box 143, Folder 20)
    - Levin, David, 1963-1965 (Box 143, Folder 21)
      (Accompanied by annotated typescripts of Levin's poetry)
    - Levine, Jocelyn, 1949-1955 (Box 143, Folder 22)
    - Levy, Beryl Harold, 1934-1994 (Box 143, Folder 23)
    - Lewine, Carol F., 1961-1973 (Box 143, Folder 24)
    - Leymarie, Jean, 1951-1985 (Box 143, Folder 25)
    - Libow, Lauren, 1983-1986 (Box 143, Folder 26)
    - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1947-1961 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Lipchitz Rehabilitation Committee, 1952 (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Lipman, Matthew, 1950-1981 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Lipsey, Roger, 1971-1980 (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Littlefield, William Horace, 1952-1965 (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Lockspeiser, Edward, 1927-1968 (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Lockspeiser, Eleanore, 1952-1953 (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - Longman, Lester Duncan, 1940-1949 (Box 144, Folder 8)
    - Longview Foundation, 1958-1975 (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Lopez, Robert S. (Robert Sabatino), 1945-1965 (Box 144, Folder 10)
    - Louis E. Stein Foundation, 1962-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Lowe, E.A. (Elias Avery), 1931-1968 (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1961-1977 (Box 144, Folder 14)
    - Lowenthal, Leo, 1937-1955 (Box 144, Folder 15)
    - Lowinsky, Edward E. (Edward Elias), 1954-1973 (Box 144, Folder 16)
    - Lozowick, Louis, 1935-1936 (Box 144, Folder 17)
    - Lurçat, Jean, 1934-1941 (Box 144, Folder 18)
    - Lurie, Boris, 1953-1956 (Box 144, Folder 19)
  - M
    - M--General, 1926-2000, (9 Folders) (Box 145, Folder 1 to 9)
    - Macdonald, Dwight, 1938-1982 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Machotka, Pavel, 1965-1981 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - MacIver, Loren and Lloyd, 1956-1989 (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Mahr, August C., 1941-1945 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1953-1977 (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Malaquais, Galy and Jean, 1946-1973 (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Manasse, Ernst Moritz, 1946-1977 (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Marcus, Ralph, 1928-1952 (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Marcuse, Herbert, 1955 (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Mares, Vaclav E., 1975-1990 (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Margolis, Joseph, 1968-1984 (Box 146, Folder 11)
    - Margolis, Lawrence, 1951-1952 (Box 146, Folder 12)
    - Mark Rothko Foundation, 1976-1979 (Box 146, Folder 13)
    - Marshak, Robert Eugene, 1946-1989 (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Masai, François, 1952 (Box 146, Folder 15)
    - Masheck, Joseph, 1976-1999 (Box 146, Folder 16)
    - Massey, Irving, 1945 (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Masson, André, 1942-1946 (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Mather, Frank Jewett, 1949 (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Matta, Roberto, 1940 (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - Matter, Mercedes, 1961-1979 (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - Mattick, Ilse and Paul, 1943-1994 (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - Mauner, George L., 1961-1989 (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - May, Morton D. (Morton David), 1952 (Box 147, Folder 8)
    - Mayer, Albert, 1935-1974 (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - McDonald, John, 1934-1937 (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - McElhatton, Mark, 1975 (Box 147, Folder 11)
    - McNulty, J. Bard (John Bard), 1978-1985 (Box 147, Folder 12)
    - Mediaeval Academy of America, 1936-1980 (Box 147, Folder 13)
    - Meiss, Millard, 1930s-1975 (Box 147, Folder 14)
    - Meloy, Caroline, 1952 (Box 147, Folder 15)
    - Meltzoff, Stanley, 1942-1974 (Box 147, Folder 16)
    - Menashe, Samuel, 1950s-1990, (7 Folders) (Box 148, Folder 1 to 7)
      (Accompanied by annotated typescripts and holograph papers of Menashe's poetry)
    - Merkel, Bernard, 1936-1948 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Merleau-Ponty, Maurice, 1949-1954 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Merton, Robert King, 1949-1971 (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Métraux, Alexandre, 1974-1984 (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.), 1937-1996 (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Metzger, Mendel, 1965-1985 (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Meyer, Bella Chagall and Piet, 1976-1983 (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Mezoughi, Noureddine, 1983-1984 (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Michelson, Annette, circa 1940s (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Margaret, Margaret K., and William, 1937-1953 (Box 149, Folder 10)
    - Miner, Dorothy Eugenia, 1933-1954 (Box 149, Folder 11)
    - Mocsanyi, Paul, 1951-1986 (Box 149, Folder 12)
    - Moholy-Nagy, László, 1944 (Box 149, Folder 13)
    - Mondolfo, Rodolfo, 1973 (Box 149, Folder 14)
    - Mondrian, Piet, 1944 (Box 149, Folder 15)
    - Monteiro, I. (Isaac), 1961-1980 (Box 149, Folder 16)
    - Morey, Charles Rufus, 1929-1942 (Box 149, Folder 17)
    - Morris, Charles W. (Charles William), 1939-1953 (Box 149, Folder 18)
    - Morris, Ivan I., 1970 (Box 149, Folder 19)
    - Morrow, Felix, 1933-1981 (Box 149, Folder 20)
    - Motherwell, Robert, 1940-1989 (Box 149, Folder 21)
      (Includes an annotated typescript of Motherwell's essay "The form of Cezanne's 'The Balcony.'" )
    - Morrow, Felix, 1933-1981 (Box 149, Folder 20)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1934-1940 (Box 149, Folder 22)
    - Munis, Grandizo, 1949 (Box 149, Folder 23)
    - Münsterberg, Hugo, 1941-1942 (Box 149, Folder 24)
    - Münz, Ludwig, 1938-1957 (Box 149, Folder 25)
    - Murray, Butler, 1927 (Box 149, Folder 26)
    - Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), 1936-1995 (Box 149, Folder 27)
  - N
    - N--General, 1930-2000, (4 Folders) (Box 150, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1959-1968 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Nachumi, Emma, 1947-1954 (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Nadejena, Lydia, 1939-1956 (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Nagel, Ernest, 1934-1978 (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - Nagatomo, Kinue, 1961-1983 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Naitove, Connie, 1960-1988 (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Nanavutty, Piloo, 1945-1948 (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Narkiss, Bezalel, 1961-1985 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Nathan, Hans, 1953-1978 (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - Nathan, Henry, 1956-1967 (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1968-1991 (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - National Gallery of Art (U.S.), 1946-1986 (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Neel, Alice, 1944-1983 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Nelligan, Emily, 1967-2001 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Nelson, Benjamin N., 1941-1973 (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - Nesjar, Carl, 1946-1996 (Box 151, Folder 9)
    - Newman, Annalee, 1970-1980 (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - Newman, Barnett, 1960-1968 (Box 151, Folder 11)
    - New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.), 1935-1984 (Box 151, Folder 12)
    - New York Review of Books, 1967-1985 (Box 151, Folder 13)
    - New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting and Sculpture, 1964-1991 (Box 151, Folder 14)
    - New York times, 1930s-1965 (Box 152, Folder 1)
      (Chiefly letters to the editor)
    - New York University, 1934-1980 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - Neufeld, Gunther and Rose, 1950-1982 (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - Neumeyer, Alfred, 1961 (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Neurath, Marie and Otto, 1937-1948 (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Neurath, Thomas and Walter, 1955-1975 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Neuss, Wilhelm, 1948 (Box 152, Folder 7)
    - Nicolson, Benedict, 1949-1966 (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - Niver, Charles, 1927-1950 (Box 152, Folder 9)
    - Nivola, Constantino, 1959-1964 (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - Nochlin, Linda, 1964 (Box 152, Folder 11)
    - Noda, Hideo, 1934-1936 (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - Nonprofit organizations -- Israel, 1970s-1980s (Box 152, Folder 13)
    - Nordenfalk, Carl Adam Johan, 1930-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 14 to 15)
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1937-1980 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Novotny, Fritz, 1932-1979 (Box 153, Folder 2 to 3)
      (File 3 includes German and English typescripts of Novotny's "Reaction against impressionism as seen from the artistic point of view" delivered at the Twentieth International Congress of the History of Art in 1961)
    - Nuclear disarmament, 1946-1947 (Box 153, Folder 4)
      (Chiefly manifestoes, brochures, and pamphlets. Includes correspondence from Zellig Harris)
    - O--General, 1924-2003, (2 Folders) (Box 154, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Oberlin College, 1952-1960 (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - O'Brady, Gertrude, 1947-1979 (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - O'Brien, Justin, 1940-1942 (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - Offner, Richard, 1952-1965 (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Ogden, R.M. (Robert Morris), 1938-1943 (Box 154, Folder 7)
    - O'keeffe, Georgia, 1952 (Box 154, Folder 8)
    - Olschki, Leonardo, 1943-1955 (Box 154, Folder 9)
    - O'Meara, John Joseph, 1953-1959 (Box 154, Folder 10)
    - Onslow-Ford, Gordon, 1941-1984 (Box 154, Folder 11)
    - Orent, Joel, 1960-1987 (Box 154, Folder 12)
    - Orienter, Anita R., 1950-1975 (Box 154, Folder 13)
    - Oxford University Press, 1937-1975 (Box 154, Folder 14)
  - P
    - P--General, 1930-2000, (6 Folders) (Box 155, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Pachter, Henry Maximilian, 1940s-1982 (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - Pächt, Otto, 1933-1972 (Box 155, Folder 8)
    - Palmer, Erwin Walter, 1947-1982 (Box 155, Folder 9)
    - Panofsky, Erwin, 1933-1968 (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - Pardee, Hearne, 1978-1994 (Box 155, Folder 11)
    - Paresce, Ella, 1940s-1964 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Partisan Review, 1937-1983 (Box 156, Folder 2)
    - Paturis, Cleo Mitchell, 19982-1993 (Box 156, Folder 3)
    - Paul, Lois, 1963-1971 (Box 156, Folder 4)
    - Paulhan, Jean, 1947 (Box 156, Folder 5)
      (Written on behalf of the members of the Comité nationale des écrivains (C.N.E))
    - Pauw-De Veen, Lydia de, 1954 (Box 156, Folder 6)
    - Pelles, Gerry, 1951-1963 (Box 156, Folder 7)
    - Pekeris, C.L., 1974-1976 (Box 156, Folder 8)
    - Penrose, Roland, Sir, 1956 (Box 156, Folder 9)
    - Péret, Benjamin, 1935-1948 (Box 156, Folder 10)
    - Perry, Geraldine, 1954 (Box 156, Folder 11)
    - Philipps-Universität Marburg. Kunstgeschichtliches Seminar, 1927-1978 (Box 156, Folder 12)
    - Phillips, Mike, 1974 (Box 156, Folder 13)
    - Pickens, Alton, 1946-1950 (Box 156, Folder 14)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1930-1986 (Box 156, Folder 15)
    - Pijoán, José, 1939-1945 (Box 156, Folder 16)
    - Pirenne, M.H. (Maurice Henri), 1940-1972 (Box 156, Folder 17)
    - Pírková-Jakobsonová, Svatava, 1947-1979 (Box 156, Folder 18)
    - Plastrik, Stanley, 1950-1981 (Box 156, Folder 19)
    - Plummer, John H., 1945-1978 (Box 156, Folder 20)
    - Polanyi, Michael L., 1946-1966 (Box 156, Folder 21)
    - Political participation, 1930-1988, (4 Folders) (Box 157, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Pollack, Robert E., 1969-1989 (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - Pool, Phoebe, 1959-1967 (Box 157, Folder 6)
    - Pope, Arthur Upham, 1932-1939 (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - Pope-Hennessy, John Wyndham, Sir, 1956-1979 (Box 157, Folder 8)
    - Porada, Edith, 1963-1983 (Box 157, Folder 9)
    - Porter, Arthur Kingsley, 1927-1933 (Box 157, Folder 10)
    - Porter, James A. (James Amos), 1938 (Box 157, Folder 11)
    - Porter, Lucy Kingsley, 1936-1950 (Box 157, Folder 12)
    - Poznanski, Edward, 1961-1967 (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - Preziosi, Donald, 1972-1985 (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - Priest, Alan, 1937 (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University, 1924-1980 (Box 158, Folder 4)
    - Prinzhorn, Hans, 1931 (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - Publishers and publishing, 1936-2001, (3 Folders) (Box 158, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Pulitzer, Joseph, 1939 (Box 158, Folder 9)
  - Q
    - Queens College (New York, N.Y.), 1937-1985 (Box 158, Folder 10)
  - R
    - R--General, 1930-2000, (8 Folders) (Box 159, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Racz, André, 1951-1975 (Box 159, Folder 9)
    - Rahv, Philip, 1937-1943 (Box 159, Folder 10)
    - Raja Singam, S. Durai, 1971-1978 (Box 159, Folder 11)
    - Ramnoux, Clémence, 1955 (Box 159, Folder 12)
    - Rand, Edward Kennard, 1927-1942 (Box 159, Folder 13)
    - Rand School of Social Science, 1944-1949 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Randall, Mercedes M. (Mercedes Moritz), 1941-1944 (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - Rannit, Aleksis, 1957-1986 (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - Ransom, John Crowe, 1940-1947 (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - Raphael, Max, 1933-1954 (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - Read, Duncan H., 1940-1967 (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - Read, Herbert Edward, Sir, 1946-1964 (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Reff, Theodore, 1961-1977 (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - Reinhardt, Ad, 1962 (Box 160, Folder 9)
      (Photocopy. Acccompanied by correspondence and clippings relating to Reinhardt)
    - Reis, Bernard, 1942 (Box 160, Folder 10)
    - Reis, Lincoln, 1929-1937 (Box 160, Folder 11)
    - Rewald, John, 1941-1988 (Box 160, Folder 12)
    - Reynal, Jeanne, 1949 (Box 160, Folder 13)
    - Reynolds, Stephanie, 1934-1955 (Box 160, Folder 14)
    - Rice, Norman N., 1933-1934 (Box 160, Folder 15)
    - Rice, Philip Blair, 1944-1955 (Box 160, Folder 16)
    - Richter, Horace, 1959-1981 (Box 160, Folder 17)
    - Riefstahl, Elizabeth and Rudolf Meyer, 1933-1937 (Box 160, Folder 18)
    - Riesman, David, 1943-1969 (Box 160, Folder 19)
    - Rigal, Louis, 1978 (Box 160, Folder 20)
    - Rivers, Larry, 1954 (Box 160, Folder 21)
    - Roazen, Paul, 1971-1995 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller, Mary C., 1935 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - Rohde, Gilbert, 1936 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Roosval, Johnny, 1935-1948 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Rorty, James, 1933-1967 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - Rosand, David, 1970-2002, (2 Folders) (Box 161, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Rose, Barbara, 1970s-1990s (Box 161, Folder 8)
    - Rosen, Hyman, 1934 (Box 161, Folder 9)
    - Rosen, James, 1980-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 161, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Rosen, James, 1986-2000, (3 Folders) (Box 162, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Rosenberg, James N. (James Naumberg), 1949-1970 (Box 162, Folder 4)
      (Includes material relating to Rosenberg's appeals to the Metropolitan Museum of Art from 1949)
    - Rosenthal, Erwin, 1943-1969 (Box 162, Folder 5)
    - Rosenthal, Henry M., 1931-1945 (Box 162, Folder 6)
    - Rosenthal, M.L. (Macha Louis), 1973-1987 (Box 162, Folder 7)
    - Rosmer, Alfred and Margarite, 1940s-1960s (Box 162, Folder 8)
    - Ross, Lillian, 1962-1964 (Box 162, Folder 9)
    - Ross, Nathanial, 1937-1960 (Box 162, Folder 10)
    - Roszak, Theodore, 1940 (Box 162, Folder 11)
    - Rothschild, Edward (Edward Francis), 1930-1938 (Box 162, Folder 12)
    - Rous, Bernard, 1928-1942 (Box 162, Folder 13)
    - Rowley, George, 1956 (Box 162, Folder 14)
    - Rozdolski, Roman, 1949-1950 (Box 162, Folder 15)
    - Rubin, James Henry, 1978-1979 (Box 162, Folder 16)
    - Rudy, Stephen, 1973 (Box 162, Folder 17)
    - Russell, Alfred, 1945-1973 (Box 162, Folder 18)
  - S
    - S--General, 1927-1980, (8 Folders) (Box 163, Folder 1 to 8)
    - S--General, 1981-2001, (4 Folders) (Box 164, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Saarinen, Aline B. (Aline Bernstein), 1936-1948 (Box 164, Folder 5)
    - Sachs, Paul J. (Paul Joseph), 1931-1952 (Box 164, Folder 6)
    - Salomon, Albert, 1946-1965 (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - Sand, Robin, 1985-1989 (Box 164, Folder 8)
    - Sandmel, Samuel, 1965-1973 (Box 164, Folder 9)
    - Sarah Lawrence College, 1936-1979 (Box 164, Folder 10)
    - Savage, Henry L. (Henry Lyttleton), 1939 (Box 164, Folder 11)
    - Sawin, David, 1940s-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 165, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Sawin, Martica, 1951-1994 (Box 165, Folder 3)
    - Saxl, Fritz, 1940-1946 (Box 165, Folder 4)
    - Schaefer, Claude, 1947-1949 (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - Schapire, Rosa, 1947 (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 1923-1927 (Box 165, Folder 7 to 9)
      (Photocopies of letters to Lillian Milgram Schapiro and Jacob Schapiro)
    - Schiff, Gert, 1960-1986 (Box 165, Folder 10)
    - Schiffrin, Jacques and André, 1946-1971 (Box 165, Folder 11)
    - Schimmel, Harold, 1960s (Box 165, Folder 12)
    - Schipper, Merle, 1973-1975 (Box 165, Folder 13)
    - Schlunk, Helmut, 1933-1982 (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - Schmalenbach, Fritz, 1938-1956 (Box 166, Folder 2)
    - Schmidt-Waehner, Trude, 1940 (Box 166, Folder 3)
    - Schocken Books, 1944-1950 (Box 166, Folder 4)
      (Includes letters from Salman Schocken, Theodore Schocken, and Hannah Arendt. Accompanied by Schapiro's notes and treatments of potential Schocken publications)
    - Scholem, Gershom Gerhard, 1961-1980 (Box 166, Folder 5)
    - Schor, Ilya, 1954-1960 (Box 166, Folder 6)
    - Schroeder, Eric, 1943-1950 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    - Schwabacher, Ethel, 1949-1957 (Box 166, Folder 8)
    - Schwartz, Delmore, 1937-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 9 to 10)
      (File 9 includes annotated typescripts of Schwartz's "Dostoevsky and the Bell Telephone Company" and "Swift." File 10 comprises correspondence with individuals other than Schwartz relating to the author's legacy)
    - Sebeok, Thomas A. (Thomas Albert), 1969-1980 (Box 166, Folder 11)
    - Secrest, Meryle Beveridge, 1978-1984 (Box 166, Folder 12)
    - Sedlmayr, Hans, 1930s (Box 166, Folder 13)
    - Sedova, Natalia, 1948-1949 (Box 166, Folder 14)
    - Segal, George, 1962-1996 (Box 166, Folder 15)
    - Segall, Berton, 1951 (Box 166, Folder 16)
    - Segre, Cesare, 1974-1987 (Box 166, Folder 17)
    - Seidel, Linda, 1975-2002 (Box 166, Folder 18)
    - Selig, Karl-Ludwig, 1975-1983 (Box 166, Folder 19)
    - Seligman, Germain, 1943-1975 (Box 166, Folder 20)
    - Seligman, Germain, 1972 (Box 633, Folder 6)
    - Seligmann, Kurt, 1940-1966 (Box 167, Folder 1)
      (Accompanied by typescripts of Schpairo's reminisces on Seligmann)
    - Semiotics, 1960s -1970s (Box 167, Folder 2)
      (Chiefly correspondence from journals relating to semiotics)
    - Serge, Victor, 1940s (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - Serra, Richard, 1985 (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - Seyrig, Henri, 1944-1965 (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - Seznec, Jean, 1941-1943 (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - Sgalitzer, Elizabeth, 1943-1945 (Box 167, Folder 7)
    - Shapiro, David, 1971-1996 (Box 167, Folder 8)
      (Accompanied by typescripts of Shapiro's poetry dedicated to Meyer Schapiro)
    - Shapiro, Romie, 1982-1984 (Box 167, Folder 9)
    - Shapley, John, 1930-1937 (Box 167, Folder 10)
    - Sharon, Hermon, 1951-1966 (Box 167, Folder 11)
    - Shattuck, Roger, 1967-1986 (Box 167, Folder 12)
    - Shaw, Howard, 1970s (Box 167, Folder 13)
    - Sherman, Claire Richter, 1976-1981 (Box 167, Folder 14)
    - Shorr, Dorothy C., 1939-1944 (Box 167, Folder 15)
    - Siegel, George, 1945-1993 (Box 167, Folder 16)
    - Sihare, Laxmi P., 1967 (Box 167, Folder 17)
    - Silbert, Bailey Saiger, 1976-1977 (Box 167, Folder 18)
    - Silone, Darina, 1954-1980 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Silvers, Robert B., 1964-1986 (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - Šimá, Josef, 1957-1971 (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - Simkhovitch, Vladimir (Vladimir Gregorievitch), 1936-1958 (Box 168, Folder 4)
      (Accompanied by photographs and signed books)
    - Simson, Otto Georg von, 1939-1975 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - Skira, Albert, 1958-1977 (Box 168, Folder 6)
    - Slive, Seymour, 1949-1987 (Box 168, Folder 7)
    - Sloane, Joseph C., 1940-1954 (Box 168, Folder 8)
    - Slonimsky, Henry, 1931-1958 (Box 168, Folder 9)
    - Slochower, Harry, 1962-1964 (Box 168, Folder 10)
    - Smith, Bernard, 1932-1937 (Box 168, Folder 11)
    - Smith College. Museum of Art, 1936-1945 (Box 168, Folder 12)
    - Smith, Norris Kelly, 1940-1995 (Box 168, Folder 13)
    - Snow, Edward A., 1981-1985 (Box 168, Folder 14)
    - Soby, James Thrall, 1945-1969 (Box 168, Folder 15)
    - Society for the Arts, Religion, and Contemporary Culture,, 1965-1969 (Box 168, Folder 16)
      (Accompanied by transcripts of lectures and talks given at the Society by Schapiro and Alfred Barr)
    - Soldati, Mario, 1930-1984 (Box 168, Folder 17)
    - Solomon, Hyde, 1949-1979 (Box 168, Folder 18)
    - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1971-1989 (Box 168, Folder 19)
    - Solow, Herbert, 1934-1962 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Sonnabend, Michael, 1945-1950 (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - Souvarine, Boris, 1941-1983 (Box 169, Folder 3)
    - Spector, Jack J., 1960-1985 (Box 169, Folder 4)
    - Stacy, Don L., 1974-1994 (Box 169, Folder 5)
    - Stanton, Frank, 1959-1963 (Box 169, Folder 6)
    - Stechow, Wolfgang, 1943-1950 (Box 169, Folder 7)
    - Steegmuller, Francis, 1941-1988 (Box 169, Folder 8)
    - Steinberg, Leo, 1985-1991 (Box 169, Folder 9)
    - Steinberg, Milton, 1941-1942 (Box 169, Folder 10)
    - Steinitz, Kate Traumann, 1942-1975 (Box 169, Folder 11)
    - Sterling, Charles, 1942-1944 (Box 169, Folder 12)
    - Stern, Henri, 1954-1960 (Box 169, Folder 13)
    - Stern, Laurent, 1962-1983 (Box 169, Folder 14)
    - Stern, Louis E., 1952-1960 (Box 169, Folder 15)
    - Sternberg, Schlomo, 1983 (Box 169, Folder 16)
    - Stibitz, George R. (George Robert), 1970 (Box 169, Folder 17)
    - Strzygowski, Josef, 1931 (Box 169, Folder 18)
    - Stix, Hugh, 1952-1958 (Box 169, Folder 19)
    - Stoddard, Whitney S., 1941-1953 (Box 169, Folder 20)
    - Stokes, May, 1938-1961 (Box 169, Folder 21)
    - Stonborough, Thomas H.W., 1962 (Box 169, Folder 22)
    - Storr, Robert, 1984-2003 (Box 169, Folder 23)
    - Strauss, Bert and Frances, 1982-1986 (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - Strauss, Ernst, 1944-1952 (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - Strayer, Joseph R. (Joseph Reese), 1940 (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - Sund, Judy, 1982-1983 (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - Swarzenski, Hanns, 1936-1963 (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - Sweeney, James Johnson, 1935-1968 (Box 170, Folder 6)
    - Swoboda, Karl M. (Karl Maria), 1954 (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - Sylvester, David, 1961-1982 (Box 170, Folder 8)
    - Syrop, Teresa, 1979-1994 (Box 170, Folder 9)
    - Szathmary, Arthur, 1949-2004 (Box 170, Folder 10)
    - Szegho, Anne, 1949-1961 (Box 170, Folder 11)
  - T
    - T--General, 1928-1996, (4 Folders) (Box 171, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Tabachnick, Anne, 1962-1986 (Box 171, Folder 5)
    - Tagliabue, John, 1967-1984 (Box 171, Folder 6)
    - Tagliacozzo, Giorgio, 1974-1984 (Box 171, Folder 7)
    - Tannhauser, Siegfried, 1938 (Box 171, Folder 8)
    - Tatarkiewicz, Władysław, 1959 (Box 171, Folder 9)
    - Taylor, Francis Henry, 1933-1942 (Box 171, Folder 10)
    - Temko, Allan, 1955-1958 (Box 171, Folder 11)
    - Tennenbaum, Silvia, 1956-1991 (Box 171, Folder 12)
    - Thomas, Norman, 1948-1958 (Box 171, Folder 13)
    - Thompson, James P.W. (Perry Williams), 1974-2003 (Box 171, Folder 14 to 15)
    - Thompson, Jim, 1951-1956 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - Thurman, Sue M., 1966-1976 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - Tieger, Arthur, 1965-1990 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - Tietze, Hans and Erika Tietze-Corant, 1935-1955 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - Tintner, Adeline R., 1935-1995 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Tomory, Peter, 1974-1978 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - Traunstein, Elsie, 1931-1932 (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - Trell, Bluma, 1981-1995 (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - Trilling, Diana, 1930s-1976 (Box 172, Folder 9)
    - Trilling, Lionel, 1931-1960 (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - Trotsky, Leon, 1938 (Box 172, Folder 11)
    - Tschacbasov, Nahum, 1937 (Box 172, Folder 12)
    - Tselos, Dimitris, 1937-1950 (Box 172, Folder 13)
    - Tuchman, Maurice, 1962-1988 (Box 172, Folder 14)